Guide to the Leslie Marmon Silko Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Leslie Marmon Silko papers
1971-2004
YCAL MSS 637
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
36.48
(45 boxes)
Papers consist of writings, research material, and audiovisual material documenting Leslie Marmon Silko's literary activity and output since the early 1970s. Writings in the collection include drafts and proofs for most of Silko's major works, the three novels Ceremony (1977), Almanac of the Dead (1991), and Gardens in the Dunes (2000), the poetry and short story collections, Laguna Woman (1974), Storyteller (1981), Sacred Water (1994), and Rain (1996), and the essays Yellow Woman and the Beauty of the Spirit (1997). In addition to other shorter and untitled works, there are clippings, photographs, personal papers, and correspondence. Audiovisual material in the collection consists chiefly of 35mm film for projects identified as Telarana and Arrowboy.
Silko, Leslie Marmon, 1948-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired through various purchases, 1992-2004.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 27-44 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Leslie Marmon Silko (1948-)
Leslie Marmon Silko was born in 1948 in Albuquerque, New Mexico, raised on the Laguna Pueblo Reservation, New Mexico, and educated at the University of New Mexico. She is the author of novels, poetry and short story collections, and other works, and the recipient of numerous awards, including the National Endowment for the Arts and poetry award (1974), Pushcart Prize for poetry (1977), and John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation grant (1981).
Biographical information taken from "Leslie Silko." Encyclopedia of World Biography. Detroit: Gale, 1998. Gale Biography In Context. Web. 3 Oct. 2012.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of writings, research material, and audiovisual material documenting Leslie Marmon Silko's literary activity and output since the early 1970s. Writings in the collection include drafts and proofs for most of Silko's major works, the three novels Ceremony (1977), Almanac of the Dead (1991) and Gardens in the Dunes (2000), the poetry and short story collections, Laguna Woman (1974), Storyteller (1981), Sacred Water (1994), and Rain (1996), and the essays Yellow Woman and the Beauty of the Spirit (1997). In addition to other shorter and untitled works, there are clippings, photographs, personal papers, and correspondence. Audiovisual materials in the collection consist chiefly of 35mm film for projects identified as "Telarana" and "Arrowboy."
Arrangement
Organized chronologically by acquisition into six groupings: May 1992 Acquisition, 1971-1980. June 1992 Acquisition, 1974, undated. July 1992 Acquisition, undated. August 1992 Acquisition, 1978-1981. July 2001 Acquisition, 1996-1999. August 2004 Acquisition, 1977-2004.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographic prints; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Native American literature; Silko, Leslie Marmon, 1948-
- May 1992 Acquisition, 1971-1980; 0.42; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  This acquisition contains drafts of writings and notes relating to Silko's first novel Ceremony (1977), the collections Laguna Woman (1974) and Storyteller (1981), the essays Yellow Woman and the Beauty of the Spirit (1997), and other work.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 232.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Sinclair Lewis Fund.
  - Ceremony, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 1)
  - Laguna Women, typescript, photocopy and printed version, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - "Tony's Story", "Yellow Woman", "Storyteller", "Uncle Tony's Goat," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 1)
  - Storyteller, drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1978 (Box 1)
  - "The Storyteller's Escape," drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Poetry, typescript and printed version, 1974-1977 (Box 1)
  - "The Dangerous Age", "Green Bicycle", "Bitter Water", "Journey", "The Sun People," typescript, undated (Box 1)
  - "Coyote Holds a Full House In His Hand", "A Geronimo Story", "Lullaby", "The Man Who Sends Rain Clouds", typescripts, 1974-1980, undated (Box 1)
  - [ Yellow Woman ], [Julian and Lena], typescript, corrected, undated (Box 1)
  - "Coyote Sits With a Full House In His Hands," typescript with autograph corrections, 1979 August (Box 1)
  - "Returning," typescript with autograph corrections, undated (Box 1)
- June 1992 Acquisition, 1974, undated; 0.21; (1 box)
  This acquisition contains additional drafts for the novel Ceremony (1977) and other short and untitled works.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 233.
  Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund.
  - Ceremony, typescript with autograph corrections, 1974 April 8 (Box 2)
  - Untitled work, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 2)
  - "The Railroad", "Christmas", untitled works, typescript, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled work, typescript and autograph manuscript, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - Ceremony: preface, typescript with autograph corrections, undated (Box 2)
  - Ad Hoc Committee of Law Students memorandum, undated (Box 2)
  - Untitled work, typescript, undated (Box 2)
- July 1992 Acquisition, undated; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  This acqusition contains drafts and proofs of Silko's first novel, Ceremony (1977), including: the publisher's master, typescript, with corrections by Silko and [Richard Seaver?]; the editor's copy, typescript, photocopy and original, with corrections and annotations by Silko and Richard Seaver; and galley proofs, with corrections by Silko.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 231.
  - Ceremony, editor's copy, typescript with autograph corrections, undated (Box 3)
  - Ceremony, galley proofs, undated (Box 3)
  - Ceremony, typescript with autograph corrections, undated (Box 4)
- August 1992 Acquisition, 1978-1981; 0.21; (1 box)
  This acquistion contains drafts of the collection Storyteller (1981), including pages deleted from the manuscript before publication, and "Estoyehmut and the Kunidyeeyah," as well as one typed letter signed from Silko to "Jeanette."
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 234.
  Purchased from Joseph the Provider, Bookseller, on the Library Associates Endowment Fund.
  - "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyah (Arrowboy and the Destroyers)," typescript, 1978 November (Box 5)
  - Typed letter signed from Leslie Silko to Jeanette, 1980 February 12 (Box 5)
  - Storyteller, typescript, [1981] (Box 5)
- July 2001 Acquisition, 1996-1999; 0.42; (1 box)
  This acquisition contains material relating to the novel Gardens in the Dunes (2000), including first and revised drafts and the advance uncorrected proof.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 156.
  Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Danford N. Barney, Jr. Fund.
  - Gardens in the Dunes, typescript, first draft, 1996; 2 (Box 6)
  - Gardens in the Dunes, typescript, revised draft, 1997; 6 (Box 6)
  - Gardens in the Dunes, advance proof, 1999 (Box 6)
- August 2004 Acquisition, 1977-2004; 34.59; (37 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 27-44 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information
  Arrangement
  Organized into two subgroups for Writings and Related Papers and Audiovisual Material.
  Writings and Related Papers features research material, drafts, proofs, and other materials relating to many of Silko's major works dating from the late 1970s. Works represented include: the novels Almanac of the Dead (1991) and Gardens in the Dunes (2000); the collections Storyteller (1980), Sacred Water (1994), and Rain (1996); the film "Arrowboy and the Witches"; the essays Yellow Woman and a Beauty of the Spirit (1997); and various shorter works. The subgroup also contains a small amount of other material, including personal papers, artwork, and correspondence.
  Audiovisual material consists chiefly of 35mm film for the projected trilogy of films, originally entitled "Stolen Rain," for which the film "Arrowboy and the Witches" was completed.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 705.
  - Writings and Related Papers
    - MSS: "Storyteller" original source materials and early drafts and revisions, approx. 150pp, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
    - MSS: "Storyteller" photocopy or original typewritten manuscript with corrections and publisher's directions 2873-4-pp, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
    - MSS: "Storyteller" set of page proofs with final corrections, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
    - MSS: "Storyteller": set of page proofs with corrections and original photograph of the Laguna pueblo with cropping instructions, undated (Box 7)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead" marked set of galleys marked "1st setting" with author's and editor's changes in red and blue pencil 716pp, 1991; 6 (Box 7)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead", undated; 7 (Box 7)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": publisher's copy of the final manuscript with corrections with cover letter dated 11/9/92 729pp, 1991-1992; 2 (Box 7)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": publisher's copy of the final manuscript with corrections with cover letter dated 11/9/92 729pp (continued), 1991-1992; 5 (Box 8)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": final (clean galley proofs) 763 pp, 1991; 8 (Box 8)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": final page proof with corrections. approx. 60 pp, 1992 (Box 8)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early typescript of the second half of the novel roughly covering pages 338-1111, 1985-1989; 6 (Box 8)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous section drafts and notes with corrections, 1985-1989 (Box 8)
    - RESEARCH MATERIALS: magazine and newspaper articles re: political background of "Almanac of the Dead", 1985-1989; 6 (Box 9)
    - RESEARCH MATERIALS: magazine and newspaper articles re: political background of "Almanac of the Dead", 1985-1989; 3 (Box 9)
    - RESEARCH MATERIALS (publications): magazine and newspaper articles re: political background of "Almanac of the Dead" Includes: "Revolution in Peru"; "Stake"; "Companero"; "Red Flag"; "Revolution"; "La Roca" etc., 1985-1989 (Box 9)
    - ORIGINAL ARTWORK: "Dream," five watercolor landscape sketches with dream notes re: the Inner Book of "Almanac of the Dead", 1984 (Box 9)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead" 3pp, [1985] (Box 9)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead" (a.k.a. "The Opal" a.k.a. "Burning Cities") 4pp, 1984 (Box 9)
    - "Almanac of the Dead" Loose notes, clippings and excerpts (dealing with code, meaning, prophecy and revolution) approx. 20pp, [1983] (Box 9)
    - RESEARCH MATERIAL: Miscellaneous publications re: political background of "Almanac of the Dead", plus notes and (5" x 5") ink drawing, [1986-1987] (Box 9)
    - FAMILY DOCUMENTS: Health care forms and application, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Three-page typed letter signed from Penelope Reedy (editor the "The Redneck Review of Literature" in Fairfield, ID), 3pp, 1987 April 1 (Box 9)
    - "Year of the Native American," celebration at Pembroke State University, P.R. materials, 1986 November (Box 9)
    - MISCELLANEOUS: One folder containing one stray poem by "mjk" and one greeting card, 1980 (Box 9)
    - MSS "Almanac of the Dead": clean "red dot" typescript which led to final typed draft (by typist Mamie Hicks) (in three parts) 1421pp, 1990-1991; 3 (Box 10)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": "Residue from the making of the final draft": miscellaneous section drafts and chapters (approx. 1500 pages) of material not used in final version, plus misc. notes and research materials approx. 1500pp, 1986-1990; 6 (Box 10)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": "Residue from the making of the final draft": miscellaneous section drafts and chapters (approx. 1500 pages) of material not used in final version, plus misc. notes and research materials approx. 1500pp (continued), 1986-1990; 6 (Box 11)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): final pilot script dated November, 1979 adapted for film by Leslie Marmon Silko and Dennis W. Carr, plus appendices, resumes and Xeroxes of location photographs 16778-79-pp (Box 11)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): one black notebook of financial records and project summary, plus one small bundle of receipts, [1982]; 2 (Box 11)
    - MSS: "Gardens in the Dunes": progressive manuscript chapter drafts of the first half of the book, running from 1995 through 1998 approx. 2000pp, 1995-1998; 5 (Box 11)
    - MSS: "Gardens in the Dunes": progressive manuscript chapter drafts of the first half of the book, running from 1995 through 1998 approx. 2000pp, 1995-1998; 20 (Box 12)
    - "Gardens in the Dunes": research material, undated (Box 12)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early original typescript with corrections of the first half of the novel entitled4 "rewrite begins October 20, 1987" running into "August 1988" page drafts with numbered pages 461pp, 1987-1988; 3 (Box 13)
    - "Almanac of the Dead": early original typescript with corrections of pages 101-405 dated 1/8/88 304pp, 1988; 2 (Box 13)
    - "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous section drafts from first half of the novel with corrections dated from 1987 and 1988 approx. 200pp, 1987-1988; 2 (Box 13)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early original typescript with corrections of pages 672-1758 dated starting from 11/15/88 through 10/11/89 and miscellaneous section drafts dating from 1987 through 1990 approx. 1800pp, 1987-1990; 7 (Box 13)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous section drafts dating from 1987 through 1990 approx. 800pp, 1987-1990; 6 (Box 14)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": final author's page proofs with corrections, plus cover letter from Simon & Schuster dated 12/3/92 and maps 1441133-134-pp, 1991-1992; 5 (Box 14)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": partial page proofs with corrections, plus cover letter from Simon & Schuster dated 12/3/92 and maps 65136-pp, 1991 (Box 14)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous "raw" autograph manuscript and typewritten page and section drafts, most with heavy corrections and amendations, some dating back to 1984, approx. 500pp, [1984-1989]; 3 (Box 14)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous "raw" autograph manuscript and typewritten page and section drafts, most with heavy corrections and emendations, some dating back to 1984, approx. 500pp, [1984-1989]; 4 (Box 15)
    - RESEARCH MATERIALS: newspaper clippings and other research re: "Almanac of the Dead", 1984-1988; 4 (Box 15)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous "raw" autograph manuscript and typewritten notes approx. 500pp, [1984-1989]; 2 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous personal papers, correspondence, notes, etc., [1980s] (Box 15)
    - MSS: "Gardens in the Dunes": original autograph manuscript notes and drafts approx. 150 pp, [1995-1998]; 2 (Box 15)
    - "Gardens in the Dunes": original typescript (part one of two parts) on heavy glossy paper with minor corrections and page numbering in felt-tip pen (pages 1-495) 495pp, [1998]; 3 (Box 15)
    - MSS: "Gardens in the Dunes": original typescript (part two of two parts) on heavy glossy paper with minor corrections and page numbering in felt-tip pen (pages 503-785) 282pp, [1998]; 2 (Box 16)
    - "Gardens in the Dunes": revised typescript with many corrections in colored ink 790pp, [1998]; 5 (Box 16)
    - "Gardens in the Dunes": publisher's corrected manuscript with corrections in red ink and red pencil and publisher's letter dated 4/1/99 746pp, 1999; 5 (Box 16)
    - "Gardens in the Dunes": autograph manuscript and typewritten corrections, ink drawings, plus correspondence with editor Michael Korda at Simon & Schuster, undated (Box 16)
    - MSS: "Gardens in the Dunes", 1996; 5 (Box 16)
    - MSS: "Gardens in the Dunes" (continued), 1996; 4 (Box 17)
    - "Gardens in the Dunes": two handmade notebooks entitled "Notes on Rain-making" with autograph manuscript notes and collage elements, 1996 (Box 17)
    - Photocopies re: "Gardens in the Dunes" book, 1996 (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): ringbound script with corrections 62pp, 1981 (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): early loose-leaf script in red folder with corrections dated July 28, 1980 approx. 60pp (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): original autograph manuscript and typewritten draft introductions approx. 20pp, [1980] (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Arrow boy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): original bound script with pasted-in and autograph manuscript corrections 62pp, [1980] (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): original dialogue script with corrections dated November, 1981 unpg. (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): photocopy of stray sound effects cue sheet approx. 10pp, [1981] (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): photographs of actors and location shots, [1981] (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): notes, proposals, script drafts and synopsis approx. 50pp, [1980-1981] (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Arrowboy and the Witches" (a.k.a. "Stolen Rain" a.k.a. "Arrowboy and the Destroyers" a.k.a. "Estoyehmuut and the Kunideeyahs"): early draft of the script with heavy corrections (in red ringbound notebook) 44190-191-pp, [1980-1981] (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Sacred Water": prospectus and rough autograph manuscript approx. 20pp, 1993 (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Sacred Water": two original signed mockups with photographs and holograph, hand-colored page layouts with two holograph sheets of explanatory notes dated 7/7/04, 1993-2004 (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Sacred Water": nine (9) variant original signed mockups with photographs and hand colored page layouts, 1993 (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Rain": galley of text for Whitney Museum book with photographs of Silko's father, Lee H. Marmon with cover letters from 1995 32196-pp, 1995-1996 (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Mural's Demise": photographic documentation and newspaper clippings re: large mural that Leslie Marmon Silko painted in Tucson, AZ in 1988, 1988-1990 (Box 17)
    - ORIGINAL ARTWORK: "Mural": original outlines and sketches for Silko's mural, plus photographs, 1988 (Box 17)
    - Photographs, and small sketchbook re: mural, 1988 (Box 17)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": early manuscript draft materials of Parts Four, Five and Six, plus outlines, drawings and two original pieces of artwork (in black spring sheet holder) approx. 120pp, [1991] (Box 18)
    - MSS: "Almanac of the Dead": miscellaneous loose notes and newspaper clippings (including "So Who Owns Death TV?" stickers), [1991] (Box 18)
    - "Almanac of the Dead": autograph manuscript notes, research materials and "Road Map of the 4th Dimension" re: "Almanac of the Dead", undated (Box 18)
    - "Almanac of the Dead": autograph manuscript notes, drawings, research materials re: philosophical underpinnings of "Almanac of the Dead" (Wittgenstein, D. T. Suzuki, Ernst Cassirer, Fukuoka, etc.), [1991] (Box 18)
    - "Almanac of the Dead": Editor's notes, queries, etc. re: copy editing, [1990-1991] (Box 18)
    - "Almanac of the Dead": Structure revisions and some deleted pages, [1991] (Box 18)
    - "Storyteller": autograph manuscript and typewritten notes toward a "Storyteller" film, including Coyote stories and poems, [1979] (Box 18)
    - "Storyteller": "1974, A St. Patrick's Day Cocktail Party in Anchorage, Alaska: typewritten draft toward a "Storyteller" film 31pp, [1979] (Box 18)
    - "Storyteller": photocopies, [1979] (Box 18)
    - "Storyteller": autograph manuscript notes and outlines, [1979-1980] (Box 18)
    - "Storyteller": "Coyote": autograph manuscript and typewritten Coyote stories and poems from "Storyteller" and elsewhere Includes: "Coyote and the Yellow Spotted Snake"; "Coyote and the Cedar Bird Ladies"; "Coyote and Skeleton Fixer"; "Coyote and His Daughters"; "Coyote Races Frog"; "Coyote Holds a Full House in His Hand" etc., undated (Box 18)
    - "The She-Bear and the Hunter": three variant manuscripts (one signed), 4pp, undated (Box 18)
    - Original ARTWORK: "The She-Bear and the Hunter": original ink drawing ("The Bear") and photocopies, 1987 (Box 18)
    - "The South Corner of Time": original typewritten draft of this poem with holograph corrections and one sheet of three small holograph poems (NOT "Almanac" material) 5pp, undated (Box 18)
    - ORIGINAL ARTWORK: original drawings and photographs, plus photocopies approx. 20pp, undated (Box 18)
    - "Dream Notes": autograph manuscript dream notes, plus photograph approx. 20pp, undated (Box 18)
    - "International Scene": autograph manuscript poetic notes 1pp, undated (Box 18)
    - MSS: "Lucy Lippard leads the vanguard...": untitled manuscript with heavy corrections re: Lucy Lippard and photography 5pp, undated (Box 18)
    - MSS: "What is Landscape?": original typewritten ("raw") drafts and revisions with heavy corrections with cover letters from George F. Thompson approx. 12pp, 1984-1986 (Box 18)
    - MSS: "The day of his funeral": untitled manuscript of autograph manuscript and typewritten notes and misc. research materials re: physics and space/time relationships approx. 12pp, 1984-1986 (Box 18)
    - ORIGINAL ARTWORK: original color drawings, plus photocopies, undated; 2 (Box 18)
    - ORIGINAL ARTWORK: original hand-colored photocopies of photographs approx. 20pp, undated (Box 18)
    - ORIGINAL ARTWORK: reproductions of photographs of desert landscapes (used for "An Essay on Rocks" in "Yellow Woman and a Beauty of the Spirit') approx. 40pp, [1996] (Box 18)
    - MSS: "The Old Man Who Died Twice": autograph manuscript of variant version of "Arrowboy and the Kunideeyah" (10pp plus five pages of original hand-colored artwork) 10224-225-pp, undated (Box 18)
    - "The Serpent": miscellaneous original typewritten and autograph manuscript page drafts and original artwork re: "Almanac of the Dead" and "Coronado and the Gran Chichimeca" film project with Marlon Brando approx. 40pp, undated (Box 18)
    - "Yellow Woman and a Beauty of the Spirit (1)": copy-edited manuscript of the Spirit with correspondence between Silko and editor Gypsy da Silva (Simon and Schuster) 136pp, 1995 (Box 18)
    - "Yellow Woman and a Beauty of the Spirit:" early collection of essays of the Spirit drafts (Incomplete, some not used) with correspondence dating from 1993 and 1994 approx. 120pp, 1993-1994 (Box 18)
    - "Almanac of the Dead": Original hand-colored "map" outline with characters and places, plus photocopies of newspaper articles, [1991] (Box 18)
    - MSS: "Ceremony": partial script of this proposed film idea, plus correspondence 21231-232-pp, 1989-1990 (Box 18)
    - Review of "Sacred Water" book 2pp, 1993 (Box 18)
    - Stray letter from John F. Beck of Black Elk Productions re: Brando film project, "Coronado and the Gran Chichimeca" 2pp, 1977 (Box 18)